Wine tastes better if you pour it from a
heavier bottle. A restaurant wants you
to drink wine. Why? Wine doesn't have a
known price anchor, so you can mark it
up like a bastard, [music] okay? You
can't charge 30 pounds a glass for a
glass of Johnny Walker Red because
people know what that costs in the shop.
But you can buy a bottle of Chateau
d'Obscure for 6 euros and charge 30
euros for it. And because it's
expensive, everybody will say it tastes
of blackcurrant, [music]
okay? What the restaurants do is they
make you think you're choosing what to
drink while actually stuffing you
royally. And this is how it happens. You
arrive, there are wine glasses already
on the table. Secondly, they bring you a
drinks menu. It's not called a drinks
list, it's called the wine [music] list.
And then there's the final touch, which
is sheer genius, they only bring one
wine list and hand [music] it to one
person. Now, there's only one drink that
you can all share. So, once the guy has
the wine list, there's only one question
you ask the rest [music] of the table,
which is red or white?